William S. Griffith Papers
William S. Griffith Papers
- Conferences
  - National Seminar on Adult Education Research, 1968; 1969 (Box 5)
  - North Central Association 1977 Annual (Community College Session) (Box 5)
  - Objectives and Methods of Research in Adult Education, 1962 (Box 5)
  - Role of Schools and Universities in Adult Education (UNESCO), 1964 (Box 5)
  - Role of Universities in Adult Education (Arab States Fundamental Education Centre), 1978; photographs only (Box 5)
  - Role of Universities in Education of Adults (International Congress of University Adult Education), 1972 (Box 5)
  - Training and Further Training of Adult Educators (European Bureau of Adult Education), 1982 (Box 5)
  - UNESCO International Conference on Adult Education, 4th Annual, 1985; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - University-based Residential Continuing Education (Kellogg Foundation), 1991 (Box 5)
- Papers (by others)
  - Cross, Duke, Haines (Box 5)
  - Houle (Box 5)
  - OECD, Savage, Sork, Sticht (Box 5)
  - Valentine, unknown (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 5)
- Reports and studies (by others)
  - Adult Basic Education, 1968-1989; United States, Canada; 4 folders (Box 5)
  - Correctional Education, 1982; 1993; Canada (Box 5)
    See also Correspondence-subject files: Correctional education
  - Extension education, 1955-1991; United States, Canada, Australia; 5 folders (Box 5)
  - Literacy, 1977-1990; United States, Canada, Iran, Latin America, international; 4 folders (Box 6)
    See also Reports and studies: Miscellaneous: Middle East
  - Women's adult education, 1979; 1992,; 1994; Canada (Box 6)
  - Miscellany
    - Africa, 1971; 1975,; 1976,; 1982,; 1990; 2 folders (Box 6)
      See also Correspondence-subject files: Nigeria
    - Asia and the Pacific, 1977; 1981,; 1983,; 1987 (Box 6)
    - Australia and New Zealand, 1977 (Box 6)
    - Canada
      - British Columbia, 1969-1992; 6 folders (Box 6)
      - Nova Scotia, 1979 (Box 6)
      - General, 1974-1992; 5 folders (Box 6, 7)
        See also Folder 1 of United States- general; Correspondence-subject files: Ministry of Education, Canada
    - China, 1964 (Box 7)
      See also International Symposium on Adult Education
    - Denmark, ca. 1976 (Box 7)
    - England and Wales, 1960-1983 (Box 7)
    - Germany, 1984 (Box 7)
    - Hong Kong, See Correspondence-subject files: Caritas Adult and Higher Education Service (Hong Kong)
    - India, See Asia and the Pacific
    - Ireland, 1986 (Box 7)
    - Israel, 1968 (Box 7)
    - Middle East, 1975; 1977,; 1978 (Box 7)
      See also Reports and studies: Literacy; Conferences: Role of Universities in Adult Education
    - New Zealand, See Australia and New Zealand
    - Norway, 1981 (Box 7)
    - Philippines, 1985; 1986,; 1990 (Box 7)
      See also Correspondence-subject files: South East Asian Ministers of Education Organization (SEAMEO)
    - Poland, 1963 (Box 7)
    - Russia, See USSR
    - Scotland, 1974-1989; includes a 1975 study by J. Alexander, "A Study of Policy, Organisation, and Provision in Community Education and Leisure and Recreation in Three Scottish Regions," 500 pp.; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Sweden, 1979-1981; 1990 (Box 7)
      International also includes some papers published by the Swedish Ministry of Education on education of the European workforce
    - Thailand, See Asia and the Pacific
    - United States
      - California, 1963-1979; 3 folders (Box 7)
      - Illinois, ca. 1974 (Box 7)
        See also Correspondence-subject files: University of Chicago; Correspondence-subject files: Illinois
      - Minnesota, 1975 (Box 7)
      - New York, 1956; 1960,; 1961,; 1965; includes text of several speeches given at Syracuse University's University College (Box 7)
      - Tennessee, 1989 (Box 7)
      - General, 1963-1991; 12 folders (Box 7, 8)
    - USSR, 1964-1965 (Box 8)
    - Wales, See England and Wales
    - International, 1980-1991; 3 folders (Box 8)
      See also Correspondence-subject files: Council of Europe (Conseil de l'Europe)
- Speeches (by others)
  - Miscellaneous speeches, 1975-1986; undated (Box 8)
    See also Correspondence-subject files: Alberta Association of Continuing Education; Correspondence-subject files: University of Chicago
- Theses (by others)
  - Ampene / Teaching styles in adult basic education, 1972 (Box 9)
  - Angeles / Electronic systems adult education course, 1981 (Box 9)
  - Apel / Adult educators' attitudes towards change, 1966 (Box 9)
  - Avoseh / Literacy as political empowerment in Paolo Freire's philosophy of education, 1991 (Box 9)
  - Beatty / Osteoporosis health education, 1986 (Box 9)
  - Bevis / Role conception and continuing learning, 1971 (Box 9)
  - Borich / Adult educators decision-making regarding advanced degrees, 1971 (Box 9)
  - Clark / Successful illiterate men, 1993 (Box 9)
  - Cookson / Achievement of Mexican-American businessmen, 1977 (Box 9)
  - Dillavou / The Swarthmore Chautauqua, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Garrison / Predictor of adult learner dropout, 1983 (Box 10)
  - Griffith / Leaders become teachers in learning organizations, 1994 (Box 10)
  - Kafka / Residential adult education effectiveness, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Kaiser / The Illinois home economics extension program, 1969 (Box 10)
  - Klever / Values and adult educational participation of clergymen, 1974 (Box 10)
  - Litchfield / The nature and pattern of participation in adult education activities, 1965 (Box 10)
  - MacNeill / Prediction of dropout in entry-level training, 1989 (Box 10)
  - Marcus / Age and perception of utility in adult education, 1976 (Box 10)
  - McLaren / Adults' persistence in university, 1990 (Box 10)
  - Mogan / Analysis of a native curriculum, 1986 (Box 11)
  - Moran / Effects of community college decentralization, 1977 (Box 11)
  - Parrish / Conceptions of marginality in adult education, 1985 (Box 11)
  - Rhodes / A life skills course for Canadian correctional institutions, 1989 (Box 11)
  - Shearon / A study of North Carolina county extension chairmen's perception of the role of the advisory board in county programming, 1965 (Box 11)
  - Sloane-Seale / Program planners' practical knowledge, 1994 (Box 11)
  - Tyrrell / Development of religious education for laymen in the U.S., 1973 (Box 11)
  - White / Professionalization process in adult education, USA, 1953-1969, 1970 (Box 11)
  - Wilson / Follow-up survey of BTSD students [BTSD = Basic Training for Skills Development], 1984 (Box 11)
  - Yeshewalul / Agent roles in Canada and the U.S., 1983 (Box 10)
- Printed material
  - Books, 1993 (Box 8)
  - Newsletters, 1974-1996; miscellaneous newsletters from a variety of organizations, most are single issues (newsletters with substantial runs or from organizations Griffith was involved with are in the Correspondence-subject files, under their organization) (Box 8)
  - Periodicals, 1955; 1986-1989; single issues of a variety of periodicals - Adult Leadership "best of" issue; one issue of REAL; two issues of Community Services Catalyst; two issues of Policy Explorations (Box 8)
  - Miscellany, miscellaneous collection of pamphlets, fliers, brochures, instruction booklets, etc from a variety of US and Canadian organizations, centers, foundations, or groups; 2 folders (Box 8)